<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-06T19:26:14+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">The Benefits of an In-Person Coding Bootcamp vs. Online Classes</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/the-benefits-of-an-in-person-coding-bootcamp-vs-online-classes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Benefits of an In-Person Coding Bootcamp vs. Online Classes" /><published>2019-03-04T21:22:15+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T21:22:15+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/the-benefits-of-an-in-person-coding-bootcamp-vs-online-classes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/the-benefits-of-an-in-person-coding-bootcamp-vs-online-classes">&lt;p&gt;With the rise of coding bootcamps as a pathway into the world of tech, there are a lot of options to choose from. One of the most important decisions to make is whether you want to attend an in-person class or an online bootcamp. While both options provide their own advantages, in-person classes tend to provide better outcomes for students for a variety of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-breakdown-in-person-vs-online-coding&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Breakdown: In-Person vs. Online Coding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing between in-person and online bootcamps is an important decision that will shape your coding skill set. Your learning experience will influence both your opinion of the coding education service and coding in general. A bad programming learning experience can turn people away from coding altogether. Here are the benefits of in-person coding bootcamps compared to online classes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;access-to-support&quot;&gt;Access to Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While online classes may be more accessible in certain cases, they lack essential elements that are important when learning a new skill. Most important among these is &lt;strong&gt;support.&lt;/strong&gt; When learning a skill that is as involved as coding, it’s crucial to have support for when you get stuck – because you will get stuck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be incredibly difficult to simulate support in an online class, but it is a key component of the in-person experience. Having the ability to get live feedback from instructors and tutors can accelerate and improve the learning process, eliminate frustration, and allow for the exchange of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/giving-coding-help.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A woman helping a man with work on his computer &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wealth and depth of information that is available when learning to code can be a blessing and a curse. Many developers will tell you that the ability to &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; is a key part of their day-to-day job. It may sound silly, but it’s true! Developers share knowledge with each other regularly, meaning there are plenty of answers on the web. This, however, can make it difficult and overwhelming to learn as a beginner. Where should you go for information? How do you know that the particular video you watched or article you read is a best practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these cases, there is no substitute for having the guidance of a professional to help you work through the problems that you’re having. Not only can they give you the answers that you need and direct you to strong, reliable online resources, they can help you solve problems through real life coding, which brings us to the next benefit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practical-application&quot;&gt;Practical Application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of learning a new skill, and especially one that is going to be the center of your new career, nothing is more important than practical application. The core goal of the coding bootcamp experience is to make sure that students are ready to land a job after graduating. Employers value the ability to understand high-level concepts, but at the end of the day, if you can’t apply the concepts to real life code, no one is going to hire you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like support, it is hard to simulate genuine practical projects through online classes. When opting for an in-person experience, you open up the world of guided coding, immediate feedback on project builds, and more. Even with the best online curriculums, it’s impossible to have the same level of responsiveness and guidance as an in-person classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;peer-collaboration&quot;&gt;Peer Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important advantage that in-person coding classes have over online options are that they allow for real life collaboration with peers in a classroom setting. Similar to having the support of instructors and tutors, being able to collaborate and build with peers improves the learning process significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning coding is an &lt;strong&gt;iterative process&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that it is best learned by doing, (often failing), and doing again. The value of having peers beside you who are going through the same process cannot be understated. It can be lonely to feel like you aren’t grasping a concept fast enough. Classmates are able to relate, provide their own unique perspectives and strengths, and help as you break down barriers. Not to mention, you’ll leave with the added benefit of having built a network of peers and friends that can help you in your future career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-pace-of-online-coding-bootcamps-can-leave-you-behind&quot;&gt;The Pace of Online Coding Bootcamps Can Leave You Behind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, many online or immersive coding bootcamps sell the idea that you can learn to be a web developer in just weeks. While this may sound attractive to someone who’s looking to switch careers, these expedited courses generally don’t allow for students to absorb the extensive amount of material required to become an effective and job-ready software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about any new skill that you’ve ever learned. Would you say that you’re willing to be a professional in it after a few weeks of study? Probably not. Web development, like anything else, is a skill that can be learned and developed. While you may be able to pick up some information over the course of a few weeks, real learning and competency comes from practice, application, and repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/javascript-html-css-books.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to these programs, in-person classes generally tend to be slower than online coding schools. A less frantic pace allows for exploration and helps the learning of a vast amount of resources sink in and stick rather than rushing through material only to forget most of it shortly afterward. For this reason, in-person grads tend to be more well-rounded and job-ready candidates after graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary-in-person-coding-bootcamps-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary: In-Person Coding Bootcamps&lt;/strong&gt; ✅&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both options have some pros and cons to weigh out before choosing. Depending on what your learning style is, in-person coding courses could be the right fit for you. In-person coding bootcamps have some strong advantages that play off of student’s strengths and shore up their weaknesses more effectively than their online counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In learning programming languages or any other subject for that matter, motivation is key to succeeding. Having &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hyperiondev.com/index.php/2019/01/15/online-vs-person-coding-bootcamps-one-best/&quot;&gt;fellow learners&lt;/a&gt; and instructors around can help bolster motivation and ensures that you won’t fall behind. Online coding bootcamps can be less expensive, however, they are also less structured and make even the most prompt of online instructors feel out of reach. Furthermore, working in teams is one of the most important aspects of efficient coding, and in-person bootcamps allow for richer teamwork experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the superior structuring and level of student interaction make in-person coding bootcamps the way to go for most students. These pros make in-person bootcamps a better choice for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are considering joining a coding bootcamp, consider Austin Coding Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-your-experience-learning-to-code-a-good-one-austin-coding-academy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Your Experience Learning to Code a Good One: Austin Coding Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy we make sure that students get the best possible in-person experience, through three key components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Our flipped-classroom approach project-based curriculum give you the practical experience that companies are looking for from bootcamp graduates. All of our students graduate with a full-built application that they can use in interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Unlimited tutoring is available to all of our students. As long as you’re willing to put in the hours to learn, we make sure that you have the support to work through any problems that you may encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Job placement is our number one priority. We have a Director of Job Placement who works with each of our students individually, and a 4-week Job Placement course to make sure that every single graduate is supported as they launch their new career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interested in learning to code with Austin Coding Academy? You can learn about the courses we have to offer, our job placement strategy, and more at&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;austincodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. If you’re ready to get started, you can fill out a quick, 5-minute application and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;apply now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With the rise of coding bootcamps as a pathway into the world of tech, there are a lot of options to choose from. One of the most important decisions to make is whether you want to attend an in-person class or an online bootcamp. While both options provide their own advantages, here is why you should opt for an in-person experience:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Four Exciting Projects That Will Inspire You to Learn JavaScript Right Now</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Four Exciting Projects That Will Inspire You to Learn JavaScript Right Now" /><published>2019-02-24T20:14:48+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-24T20:14:48+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript-right-now-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript (JS) is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackify.com/popular-programming-languages-2018/&quot;&gt;most commonly-used coding language&lt;/a&gt; for developers in 2019. JS earned its popularity because it’s easy to learn, dynamically typed, fast to run, and works across most platforms, including all modern web browsers. Coders &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/which-aca-track-is-right-for-you&quot;&gt;from all different specialties&lt;/a&gt; will need a basic understanding of JavaScript to complete most designs—especially front-end designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some impressive projects that might inspire you to want to start learning JavaScript now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-technology-and-talking-plants&quot;&gt;Smart technology and talking plants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart technology has the potential to improve our healthcare, revolutionize our workplaces, and customize our homes. As this trend in smart tech progresses, we may find ourselves living in a sci-fi utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One appealing smart-tech project uses JavaScript code to create &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webondevices.com/the-arduino-plant-with-javascript-voice-recognition/&quot;&gt;smart plants&lt;/a&gt;. Smart plants use sensors to detect soil moisture, temperature, and other factors important for plant health. Advanced voice recognition software and text-to-voice capability makes it easy to interact with smart plants and simplifies the plant maintenance process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart technology is an emerging field that will soon change our lives. Learning JavaScript could provide you with the skill set necessary to land a job in this new and exciting industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drones-that-fly-themselves&quot;&gt;Drones that fly themselves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drones aren’t just fun; they’re useful, with applications in aerial photography, package deliveries, safety inspections, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virgin.com/virgin-unite/business-innovation/humanitarian-sky-drones-disaster-response&quot;&gt;humanitarian efforts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using JavaScript, it’s possible to build self-driving drones. Lines of JS code can command drones to auto-hover, perform barrel rolls, and run into red objects like a matador would do with a bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At events like &lt;a href=&quot;http://dronegames.co/&quot;&gt;Drone Games&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nodecopter.com/&quot;&gt;Nodecopter&lt;/a&gt;, programmers use software to see who can make the coolest drone. They often reuse open-source code snippets to program features like voice to text, face recognition, and advanced directional 3D movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these projects are fun, they can also help you land a job. The drone job market will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/budget-finance/Drone-Related-Job-Growth-to-Outpace-Predictions.html&quot;&gt;grow faster than predicted&lt;/a&gt;, and some universities even offer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/budget-finance/Drone-Related-Job-Growth-to-Outpace-Predictions.html&quot;&gt;degrees in drone technology&lt;/a&gt;. Industries that will use drones include the military, real estate, construction, filmmaking, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://uavcoach.com/uav-jobs/#guide-5&quot;&gt;insurance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about what it takes to get into the drone industry by reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.ieee.org/jobs/content/Drones-are-a-big-job-opportunity-but-for-new-engin-2017-02-10&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-apps-that-dominate-industries&quot;&gt;Mobile apps that dominate industries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brainhub.eu/blog/famous-apps-built-with-react-native/&quot;&gt;Many apps&lt;/a&gt; use the JS react native framework, but the Facebook ads app is a particularly shining example. &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.fb.com/developer-tools/react-native-for-android-how-we-built-the-first-cross-platform-react-native-app/&quot;&gt;Facebook uses JS&lt;/a&gt; to calculate complex variables like ad formats, time zones, dates, and currencies. Many of these features are accessible through an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.mybridge.co/amazing-javascript-projects-for-the-past-year-v-2018-2f114c6bd70a&quot;&gt;open source JavaScript code&lt;/a&gt;. The react native framework is also perfect for creating an integrated user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When tech giants like Facebook use JS, it shows that the language is not limited to small app projects. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/blogs/5-benefits-of-reactjs-to-brighten-a-cloudy-day&quot;&gt;JavaScript has key advantages&lt;/a&gt; that make it perfect for projects of any size. Learning JS can help developers build projects at any scale—big or small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;websites-to-inspire-action&quot;&gt;Websites to inspire action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website design skills are growing in demand. Companies spend a lot of time and money trying to drive traffic to their website. Designers who can convert that traffic into paying customers are especially competitive in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is the perfect tool for building &lt;a href=&quot;http://webdesignerwall.com/trends/30-truly-interactive-websites-built-css-javascript&quot;&gt;stunning websites.&lt;/a&gt; The code is fast, and object manipulation makes it possible to create amazing interactive designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning JavaScript will prepare you for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-developer&quot;&gt;lucrative career&lt;/a&gt;, but you don’t have to wait until after graduation to get started. Working on side projects is a great way to hone your skills and build up your &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-are-hiring-managers-looking-for-in-a-developers-portfolio&quot;&gt;developer’s portfolio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some amazing websites to inspire your next web-design project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://windowwonderland.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Window Wonderland&lt;/a&gt;: This website puts you right in the middle of New York City’s holiday shopping experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cavalierchallenge.com/&quot;&gt;Cavalier Challenge&lt;/a&gt;: This online game immerses you in a experience right from the get-go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airview.blueair.com/&quot;&gt;Air View&lt;/a&gt;: Air View is an innovative way to visualize abstract air quality data to make it feel “real.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keyideas.net/&quot;&gt;Key Ideas&lt;/a&gt;: Key Ideas is a film-production agency that uses their website to showcase their unique skills and services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some ACA students who made projects with JavaScript to improve their portfolio and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/5-ways-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austins-tech-industry&quot;&gt;land their first developer job&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/student-project-highlight-jon-gucciardi&quot;&gt;Jon Gucciardi&lt;/a&gt; built his own messaging app, and landed a job as a software developer for Verizon Wireless.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/student-project-highlight-greg-devany&quot;&gt;Greg Devany&lt;/a&gt; designed a website and app for helping users find coupons for restaurants. He’s used it as the cornerstone of his resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-learning-javascript-today&quot;&gt;Start learning JavaScript today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These projects highlight why JavaScript is such a desirable skill to have. JavaScript developers get to work on fun tasks while earning &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-developer&quot;&gt;a great salary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACA offers you the fast track to a coding career. You’ll learn the most in-demand skills from teachers who also work full-time as developers. After graduation, you’ll get access to our job placement network to connect you with the position of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to start your path towards a rewarding career? &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;schedule a call with our staff&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.austincodingacademy.com/schedule-a-campus-tour&quot;&gt;tour the campus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/why/&quot;&gt;Learn how ACA can help&lt;/a&gt; jumpstart your software development career today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">JavaScript (JS) is the most commonly-used coding language for developers in 2019. JS earned its popularity because it’s easy to learn, dynamically typed, fast to run, and works across most platforms, including all modern web browsers. Let’s look at some impressive projects that might inspire you to start learning JavaScript now:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What to Do When You Want to Change Careers</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/what-to-do-when-you-want-to-change-careers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What to Do When You Want to Change Careers" /><published>2019-02-21T21:32:48+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T21:32:48+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/what-to-do-when-you-want-to-change-careers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/what-to-do-when-you-want-to-change-careers/">&lt;p&gt;The thought of changing careers is exciting to many people at one time or another. With your goals and ambitions no longer constrained by your old career path, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/5-signs-you-need-to-change-careers&quot;&gt;a career change&lt;/a&gt; may open up your potential and let you surprise yourself. Pursuing a career you’re excited about can also provide a stronger sense of purpose and passion for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that excitement can vanish if you’re afraid changing careers is too risky or complicated. The truth is, you don’t have to take irresponsible risks when exploring new career options. You can even prepare for a career change while &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/&quot;&gt;keeping your current job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some strategies that can help you make a transition without the risk of going broke:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-clear-about-what-you-want&quot;&gt;Be clear about what you want&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to go to all the effort of changing careers, only to fall into another career you dislike. That’s why it’s critical you consider what career factors do you value most. With a clear idea of what you want, you can better choose a profession that’s in line with your goals and aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, use the experience from your current job to pinpoint what to avoid in a future career. Open a document or grab a piece of paper and write down a list of the exact tasks you dislike in your current role. Think critically about WHY you don’t enjoy these tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of why you may not like a task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skill mismatch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much/too little human interaction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feels unrewarding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tasks are too repetitive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now repeat the process, but list the tasks at your job you actually enjoy (come on… there must be &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; you like). Again, ask why you enjoy these tasks. You can now use these two lists to help determine what you are looking for from a new line of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider is the impact your new career will have on the rest of your life. Here are some examples questions to ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you want to work from home?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the option of starting a business important?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What income level do you want to achieve?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you want absolute choice over where you live?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What job outlook are you comfortable with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorm-careers&quot;&gt;Brainstorm careers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand what’s important to you, brainstorm some careers that will give you what you want. The key to effective brainstorming is to think openly about your potential new direction. Remember to think about why you liked the tasks you listed above. Don’t limit yourself because of preconceived notions of what you think a career is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebalance.com/free-career-aptitude-tests-2059813&quot;&gt;taking a free aptitude test&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com/advice/8-brilliant-books-that-will-lead-you-to-your-dream-job&quot;&gt;reading a career book&lt;/a&gt;. Explore websites like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/a&gt; to get a better idea of career outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our students love coding because it’s a career that offers the flexibility to work wherever you want. It is also highly in demand, making it a high-paying career field. ACA students earn an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchup.org/bootcamps/austin-coding-academy&quot;&gt;average starting salary of $64,000&lt;/a&gt;. For entrepreneurial types, there are also a lot of ways to branch off and start your own projects/businesses with coding skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reach-out-to-people-in-your-desired-field&quot;&gt;Reach out to people in your desired field&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An underrated strategy for &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/5-ways-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austins-tech-industry&quot;&gt;exploring new work&lt;/a&gt; is connecting with mentors. Talking to friends and family is great if they’re in your exact field of interest. For most of us, that won’t be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you’ll want to reach out to people who’ve already accomplished what you want to do. If you’re looking to become a developer, you can always connect with &lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/austin-coding-academy-1&quot;&gt;ACA’s alumni network&lt;/a&gt;. Another way to network with professionals in your desired field is to reach out to them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Google or Indeed/LinkedIn to find companies that hire your desired position.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the people currently in the position you want by searching directory pages or the employee section of Linkedin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send them an email or ask to “connect” if on LinkedIn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask them questions about their career choice to see if it’s the right choice for you too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this can be useful information, take their feedback with a grain of salt, because many people tend to speak highly of their own careers. When you reach out like this, it often makes people feel like their work is important (and by extension, that &lt;em&gt;they’re&lt;/em&gt; important). They probably wouldn’t want to lose face by confessing to a stranger that their job sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some questions to ask questions to get honest answers without forcing them to either sugarcoat the truth about their jobs or hurt their ego:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What daily task do you like most at your job?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What task do you like the least?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What personality traits would someone need to be good at this job?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is one thing you wish you knew before starting your career?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s one big misconception you had about the field before you started?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;try-it-out-first&quot;&gt;Try it out first&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve done a lot of prep work at this point. Now it’s time to get your hands dirty and actually do some work in the position you’re interested in. It’s easy to fantasize about why a career might be amazing, but actually doing the work will give you a more accurate idea of what it takes. A test run is important to understand if you’re getting into the right field before investing too much time or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get started with the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take an introduction class (here’s some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/o/austin-coding-academy-10937668459&quot;&gt;great local events&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take freelance work on job sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/&quot;&gt;upwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask the people you emailed for internship opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re ready, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/blog/2017/05/26/20-tips-for-landing-your-first-job-in-web-development&quot;&gt;get an entry-level job&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;commit-to-change&quot;&gt;Commit to change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve decided on your career and given it a test run, it’s time to commit. Look up the career paths by using a tool like the “Common Career Paths” section on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.payscale.com/research/US/Job=Web_Developer/Salary&quot;&gt;PayScale&lt;/a&gt;. This is helpful to get a better idea of what you want your long-term career to look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now take time to invest in your education. Start learning everything you can to be competent in your field. Make sure to learn practical skills that will be attractive to employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great option for educating yourself is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;take a class&lt;/a&gt;. At ACA, you’ll be able to learn the skills to get a coding job you love. You also get the added benefit of support from your peers and teachers to help you succeed and access to a network of experienced professionals required to help land an amazing job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to jump into an exciting coding career &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;apply today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The thought of changing careers is exciting to many people at one time or another. With your goals and ambitions no longer constrained by your old career path, a career change may open up your potential and let you surprise yourself. But that excitement can vanish if you’re afraid changing careers is too risky or complicated. Here are some strategies that can help you make a transition while minimizing risk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Characteristics of a Successful Web Developer</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Characteristics of a Successful Web Developer" /><published>2019-02-21T21:04:26+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T21:04:26+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer/">&lt;p&gt;Are there certain characteristics that make you a better web developer than others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking into the tech scene can be very intimidating - it seems like every day there is a trendy new JS library to learn and another class of coding school graduates to compete with. If you spend any time scouring job boards, you’ll also see this reflected in entry-level or junior web development jobs requiring a wider knowledge base from their applicants than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, you would think that candidates with the deepest ocean of knowledge would always land the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may come as a surprise to you – as the web developer role spends most of their time in front of a computer screen, handling highly technical issues with complicated code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, I’ve been on both sides of the hiring process for tech roles, and have witnessed the smartest candidates get passed over for someone who is a better “fit” for the role or company. I’ve seen the sharpest web developers crumble and crack under the pressure of deadlines, or lose their patience and professionalism from constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great code doesn’t always translate into a great hire. While it definitely helps, there is more to being a successful web developer than a mind rich in technical knowledge. Here are seven characteristics common in web developers - other than technical skills - who are successful at their job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-passion-for-knowledge&quot;&gt;A passion for knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-2.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-2.jpg =300x150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology is always evolving, and the skills and abilities needed in today’s tech scene can get outdated quickly. It’s important to have a passion for learning and the desire to keep up with the latest trends. As newer versions of languages, libraries and frameworks roll out, you will be expected to not only know these changes, but be a subject matter expert within your company. Don’t confuse this with technical skills - you can still love to learn without being the sharpest crayon in the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes beyond a willingness to educate yourself. You should embrace the inevitable challenges that come with the job, and develop a great habit for researching possible solutions. If you love the work and the challenge that it presents, you will be successful at your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-teammate&quot;&gt;Great teammate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-3.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-3.jpg =300x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web developer rarely works alone. Good software is commonly built by a whole development team comprised of many dynamic roles. Being able to take on a team mentality can be critical to the success of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the immediate team, web developers will also be expected to work with business owners, sales and marketing staff, and other developers outside of the team or company in order to achieve a wider project scope. In these cases, the ability to lead or act as the representative of your team in a meeting or other professional scenario is a soft skill that helps you stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creative-problem-solver&quot;&gt;Creative problem solver&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-4.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-4.jpg =300x150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing code for a software program or designing website from scratch is incredibly difficult – much like trying to solve a complex math equation or write a novel. A great developer thrives on finding ways to make things work, no matter the challenge, and sometimes needs to get creative to find a working solution. You want to try to avoid the phrase “It can’t be done” when you are pitched a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great working knowledge of the language or framework you are using is a must. If you understand the limitations or abilities of the code you are using, you can awaken more creative and efficient ideas for solving problems. And the light bulbs will turn on faster and brighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-plan-for-everything&quot;&gt;Ability to plan for everything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-5.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-5.jpg =300x150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than jumping head-first into a project, a wise and cautious web developer will first learn as much as possible about the desired end product. Once this step is completed, the developer will then plan out the entire structure of the project before typing out one line of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a critical step - as one little oversight can throw a project deadline off by weeks or even months. Complete your wireframe the entire site and get approval before creating your first template. Ensure your routes and controllers are properly configured. If you don’t properly plan for as much as possible, you better have…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-debugging-skills&quot;&gt;Great debugging skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-6.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-6.jpg =300x150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my current job, I identify and solve issues on large, e-commerce websites. Basically, I help fix bad code written by their in-house developers that they couldn’t solve themselves. What I found more shocking than how simple the mistakes are – was how often the developers themselves did not know how to properly debug their own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing and developing code is only part of a web developer’s job. They are also expected to identify the root of a problem quickly and effectively. Instead of spending hours making blind changes, developers need to have a solid handle on the variety of Web Developer Tools provided by modern browsers such as Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and Edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accelerated-failure-mentality&quot;&gt;“Accelerated Failure” Mentality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-7.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-7.jpg =300x150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fail Fast”, “Fail Better”, “Fail Forward” are all popular mantras used by startups and tech giants in Silicon Valley. If you aren’t failing, you aren’t learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely does code get written correctly the first time. This is why we plan for everything and know how to debug anything. It’s important to see bugs and errors in your code as a challenge rather than a sign of defeat. Successful web developers embrace the challenge of failure and tend to bounce back with bigger and better solutions to these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business-sense&quot;&gt;Business Sense&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Imported_Blog_Media/blog-5-31-17-8.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;height=150&amp;amp;name=blog-5-31-17-8.jpg =300x150&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great developer can look beyond the project they are working on and see the big picture for the business. A savvy business sense can lead to new applications or automated processes focused on more saving time and money for a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to an MBA or a passion for macro-economics to be business-savvy, but showing an interest in areas of the business outside of your direct scope can lead to a better understanding of your company’s big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t easy becoming a web developer - and to excel in the industry takes more than an encyclopedia of coding knowledge. There are certain characteristics that successful web developers share not commonly taught in many CS degree programs or coding schools. You need to have a variety of soft skills on top of your technical abilities to stand out in the crowd when applying for a job in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching these soft skills is one way our program stands out in the crowd of coding schools. Our program not only teach our students the technical skills every full-stack web developer needs, every campus provide workshops and break-out sessions in order to provide a wider educational foundation in soft skills proven to help any fledgling web developer succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning both the hard and soft skills necessary for a successful coding career, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/&quot;&gt;course schedule&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;fill out an application&lt;/a&gt; to save your spot in the next class.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Great code doesn’t always translate into a great hire. While it definitely helps, there is more to being a successful web developer than a mind rich in technical knowledge. Here are seven characteristics common in web developers - other than technical skills - who are successful at their job:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Get a Job as a Web Developer in Austin’s Tech Industry</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/how-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austin-tech-industry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Get a Job as a Web Developer in Austin's Tech Industry" /><published>2019-02-21T20:59:29+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T20:59:29+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/how-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austin-s-tech-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/how-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austin-tech-industry">&lt;p&gt;Looking for your first web development job in Austin can seem extremely daunting. This is especially true if you are new to town and don’t have a built-in network of friends to help you get a foot in the door at a tech company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fear not! We’ve rounded up some great resources and events that can help you find a web development job in Austin. Take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-go-to-career-fairs&quot;&gt;1. Go to Career Fairs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career fairs are a great opportunity to get a feel for different companies. Unlike submitting an application and hoping you hear back from an employer, career fairs allow you to meet recruiters and managers in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a little facetime gives you the opportunity to sharing your personality and enthusiasm with potential employers. This connection is much more valuable than all the stats listed in plethora of applications buried in their email folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-use-job-boards-to-find-web-development-jobs-in-austin&quot;&gt;2. Use Job Boards to Find Web Development Jobs in Austin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can always type “web development jobs in Austin” on Monster, LinkedIn, Indeed, and other popular job sites. But if you haven’t noticed yet, these sites are getting very saturated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more tailored results, here are the places to look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-web-designers-and-developers&quot;&gt;For Web Designers and Developers:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.authenticjobs.com/&quot;&gt;Authentic Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/jobs&quot;&gt;Angel List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/&quot;&gt;UpWork&lt;/a&gt; (formerly elance and odesk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.krop.com/&quot;&gt;Krop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupers.com/&quot;&gt;Startupers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://weworkremotely.com/&quot;&gt;We Work Remotely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-web-developers&quot;&gt;For Web Developers:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://careers.stackoverflow.com/jobs&quot;&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://androidjobs.io/&quot;&gt;Android Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jobs.coreint.org/&quot;&gt;Core Intuition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-build-out-your-professional-network-both-online-and-in-person&quot;&gt;3. Build Out Your Professional Network, Both Online and In Person&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be surprised how often people land jobs through their network. The cliche “It’s not &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know but &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you know” is so common for reason. Getting an awesome web development job in Austin means building your online network and going to meetups. If you’re already doing those things, kudos. You’re killing it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re new to the scene, here are some groups and meetups you should check out to start meeting other movers and shakers in Austin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Austin-Web-Design/&quot;&gt;Austin Refresh Meetups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Austin-Coding-Academy/&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy Meetups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://capitalfactory.com/events/&quot;&gt;Capital Factory Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/austindigitaljobs/&quot;&gt;Austin Digital Jobs Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thebashh.com/&quot;&gt;B.A.S.H.H. (Big Ass Social Happy Hour)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-find-a-mentor-in-the-industry&quot;&gt;4. Find a Mentor in the Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re rubbing elbows in Austin’s development community and your LinkedIn network is growing, it’s time to find a mentor in the tech industry. But be careful not to be a phony; make sure you are building genuine relationships with people you trust and admire. When it comes to asking for help from a more established person in the industry, here’s a good rule of thumb: aim to &lt;em&gt;add&lt;/em&gt; value first and &lt;em&gt;ask&lt;/em&gt; for value second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you feel like you’ve connected with someone in the industry, try experimenting with small asks until you can build up to asking for an in-person meetup over a coffee or a pint. Use this time to casually discuss your job search, your skill set, and provide insights about what kind of career opportunities you’re looking for. Their experience in the Austin tech scene can give you an inside track, especially when it comes to the interviewing process. They can also point you in the direction of more specialized events, meetups, online communities, or other resources that might help you on your path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/kathycaprino/2014/09/21/how-to-find-a-great-mentor-first-dont-ever-ask-a-stranger/&quot;&gt;Here’s a great guide&lt;/a&gt; to connecting with possible mentors through social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-practice-mock-interviews-and-questions&quot;&gt;5. Practice Mock Interviews and Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a mentor and have built a good rapport, you may want to ask to practice a mock interview with them. Most likely, you will stumble a few times and eat some humble pie, but this practice can be really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub has a great resource of &lt;a href=&quot;http://h5bp.github.io/Front-end-Developer-Interview-Questions/&quot;&gt;front-end developer interview questions&lt;/a&gt;. The internet is swimming with example questions and answers, so don’t be shy with your Googlin’ skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two resources to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iI6jiwoqxg4&quot;&gt;A video&lt;/a&gt; about how to prepare for a job interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-are-hiring-managers-looking-for-in-a-developers-portfolio&quot;&gt;What hiring managers want to see in a portfolio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-paid-internships&quot;&gt;Bonus: Paid Internships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still struggling to get your foot in the door, and are willing and able to put in another three months of “on-the-job” training, there are plenty of startups and tech companies (such as uShip, IBM, and Dell) that offer decent paid web development internships somewhere in the $25-$28/hour range. These companies use their internship pools for new hires, and most entry-level jobs are filled this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a full-time job finding a job, and every little advantage helps. Doing these five things will help you position yourself for not only short-term gains, but long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and may the function be with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Looking for your first web development job in Austin can seem extremely daunting. This is especially true if you are new to town and don't have a built-in network of friends to help you get you foot in the door at a tech company. Fear not! We’ve rounded up some great resources and to help. Take a look:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Signs You Need to Make a Career Change</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/5-signs-you-need-to-make-a-career-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Signs You Need to Make a Career Change" /><published>2019-02-21T20:32:26+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T20:32:26+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/5-signs-you-need-to-make-a-career-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/5-signs-you-need-to-make-a-career-change/">&lt;p&gt;On Sunday nights, what do you generally feel about the week ahead of you? Are you energized, enthusiastic, and ready to hit the ground running on Monday morning? Or do you feel mopey, exhausted, and full of dread? If you fall into the second camp, it may be time to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average American spends at least 40 hours a week at work for several decades. A career represents too much of your lifespan for it to be something that makes you miserable. In some cases, the Sunday night blues aren’t a symptom of the career itself, but external factors like the commute or an unappealing workspace. Those issues can generally be remedied with some small tweaks— some new podcasts to make the commute more enjoyable, working from home a few days a week, taking a walk around a nearby park during lunch, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases, however, the issue isn’t the office, or the team you work with, or anything that can be easily fixed; sometimes, the problem is the career itself. While the thought of making such a huge overhaul may be daunting, here are some signs it’s time to take a leap and move into a new career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-feel-drained&quot;&gt;You feel drained&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any job, in any field, there will be days where even the most experienced and talented people will leave feeling exhausted or defeated. In fact, occasional periods of failure or experimentation are crucial to professional development. But if you’re finding yourself perpetually drained, and getting out of bed for work in the morning feels like a struggle, it might be time to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;youre-bored&quot;&gt;You’re bored&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t find your work to be challenging enough to keep you engaged, you’re not working up to your potential. At work, you should ideally be challenged enough to feel invigorated, but not so challenged that you get discouraged. If that doesn’t sound like your job, it’s time to make a change; that may mean asking for a promotion or additional projects to stretch yourself, or it might mean it’s time to find a new field altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;there-arent-opportunities-for-growth&quot;&gt;There aren’t opportunities for growth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, your talents and interests would be nurtured in your company, and there would be abundant opportunities for professional and personal development. In reality, many people go to work every morning unsure about whether their potential is being recognized and valued. If you find that you keep bumping up against the upper end of what your company can offer you in terms of development, you may want to start considering your next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-arent-satisfied-with-the-pay-potential&quot;&gt;You aren’t satisfied with the pay potential&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean it’s time to run out the door because you’re not earning a six-figure salary in your first year at a company. However, if you know that realistically, your career path has a cap on the potential salary you can earn (and that number doesn’t align with your personal goals) it might be time to start considering potential alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-dont-feel-a-sense-of-pride-or-purpose&quot;&gt;You don’t feel a sense of pride or purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A career should be about so much more than just paying the bills. It should fill you with pride, make you feel invigorated and challenged, and give you a reason to greet the day. If you find yourself getting envious of people in other fields for the excitement they have about their work, here’s an important thing to remember: &lt;em&gt;you can have that too&lt;/em&gt;, but getting there might require making a big change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-started-now&quot;&gt;Get started now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel stuck, uninspired, and undervalued in your job, the thought of making a big transition into a new career might fill you with a mixture of excitement and fear. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/how-to-achieve-big-goals-this-year&quot;&gt;Accomplishing ambitious goals&lt;/a&gt; isn’t easy, but the effort involved in building a career that makes you feel challenged, appreciated, and engaged is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The average American spends at least 40 hours a week at work for several decades. A career represents too much of your lifespan for it to be something that makes you miserable. While the thought of making such a huge overhaul may be daunting, here are some signs it’s time to take a leap and move into a new career path.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Tips to Help You Learn Coding Faster</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/5-tips-to-help-you-learn-coding-faster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Tips to Help You Learn Coding Faster" /><published>2019-02-21T20:22:14+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T20:22:14+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/5-tips-to-help-you-learn-coding-faster</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/5-tips-to-help-you-learn-coding-faster/">&lt;p&gt;Mastering a new skill can take years of focus and practice. But what if you want to speed things up a little? When it comes to getting a job as a developer, you may not want to wait years to get started. Good news: there are some things you can do in your spare time every day that will help you get better in less time. Here are five things to try to learn programming faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-practice-every-day-on-real-projects&quot;&gt;1. Practice every day on real projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any other job, having hands-on experience is a must. Whether it’s for your own personal website, or a project for a close friend or family member, try to find actual assignments to give yourself for practice. When you get to flex your coding muscles on things that will actually live on the internet, you put yourself into an &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/how-the-principles-of-language-learning-can-help-you-code-better&quot;&gt;immersive environment&lt;/a&gt;, giving you a better chance to become fluent quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-use-free-coding-websites-for-tutorials-and-projects&quot;&gt;2. Use free coding websites for tutorials and projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for aspiring developers, there is no shortage of resources online these days. Using platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;CodeAcademy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/&quot;&gt;edX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://agupieware.com/&quot;&gt;aGupieWare&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeavengers.com/&quot;&gt;Code Avengers&lt;/a&gt;, you can access free tutorials and cool project prompts. On any of these sites, you’ll work on interactive platform, learning languages such as JavaScript, PHP, and Python to create web apps, games, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-make-and-use-flashcards&quot;&gt;3. Make and use flashcards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can handle the flashbacks to high school, go old-school and use flashcards! In the same way they helped you master vocabulary words for the SAT, flashcards can help you learn common terms for whatever coding language you’re trying to master. They’re also portable, meaning you can break them out at breakfast, on the bus to work, or when you need a five-minute break from work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have index cards handy, hate your handwriting, or are just too embarrassed to be seen holding flash cards in public, you can also use an app like &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/flashcards+-by-chegg-free/id408490162?mt=8&quot;&gt;Flashcards+&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/studyblue/id323887414&quot;&gt;StudyBlue&lt;/a&gt; to get the same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-blog-about-it&quot;&gt;4. Blog about it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to put new knowledge to the test is to try to explain it to someone else. Consider creating a personal blog to help you document your journey to becoming a masterful developer. In addition to serving as a great reminder of how far you’ve come, blogging about what you’re learning helps cement new concepts so they can connect to the bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, it can also be a great way to network. By connecting with other developers, whether they’re more or less experienced than you, you have the opportunity to share what you’ve learned and take advantage of the knowledge of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a great writer? You may want to consider recording yourself and creating a vlog to share your learnings in video form instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-take-a-class-or-coding-bootcamp&quot;&gt;5. Take a class or coding bootcamp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootcamps and classes are another excellent way to learn programming faster. Classes are instructor-led, allowing students to get hands-on experience and work directly with professors. Taking a front end or back end track class through a program like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy&lt;/a&gt; takes students through the beginning, intermediate, and advanced lessons necessary to prepare for full time developer roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing with your organization, changing careers, or getting serious about a hobby all starts with mastering the subject matter. If you’re a programmer or a future programmer in the Austin area, we’d love to talk to you about how our 10-week courses can help you transition into a career as a developer or sharpen your existing skills. &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Learn more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Mastering a new skill can take years of focus and practice. But what if you want to speed things up a little? When it comes to getting a job as a web developer, you may not want to wait years to get started. Good news: there are some things you can do in your spare time every day that will help you get better in less time. Here are five things to try to learn programming faster.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What are Companies Looking for in a Web Developer’s Portfolio?</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-are-companies-looking-for-in-a-web-developers-portfolio" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are Companies Looking for in a Web Developer's Portfolio?" /><published>2019-02-21T20:16:21+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T20:16:21+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-are-companies-looking-for-in-a-web-developer-s-portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-are-companies-looking-for-in-a-web-developers-portfolio">&lt;p&gt;If you’re just starting out on your path as a developer without much or any experience to show off in your portfolio, the road ahead may seem daunting. Your portfolio is more than a showcase of projects and work samples. Your portfolio is your digital space that invites hiring managers to learn more about you and how you would be a great fit in their company and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what makes a great developer portfolio? What are hiring managers looking for when they review one? Let’s take a closer look at the important elements that make up a solid developer portfolio that will land you an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-started-now&quot;&gt;Get started now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your developer portfolio is an ongoing, evolving project. Don’t wait until you start sending out your resume to start developing your portfolio. Get started as soon as possible so you’re not rushing to get something together before a recruiter takes a look. If you’re still taking classes, add projects to your portfolio as you complete them. Then, continue to update and improve your portfolio with every project you work on or goal you meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;show-your-skills&quot;&gt;Show your skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the cornerstone of your portfolio. Not every hiring manager is the same. Some may look at your resume first before moving to your portfolio. Others may want to follow a link to your hosted projects or your Github repository of projects. It’s important that you keep up with each of these elements, so no matter the method of the hiring manager, you’re prepared to show off your work, skills, and technological capabilities and how you solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t spend too much time trying to build the next great app that does a new thing or solves a different problem but ends up being poorly ‘spec’ed out. You may end up burdened by the amount of decisions and get stalled in your project. Your portfolio doesn’t need to be limited to work someone else commissioned or paid you to do. Find a project or app to clone and show a hiring manager how you would solve the problems with that app to make it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Colten, Chief Technology Officer and Lead Instructor at Austin Coding Academy, says he looks for “a strict following of coding conventions that can span different coding languages, especially if I’m considering hiring them in a language that isn’t their preferred language.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the type of role and breadth of technologies used, hiring managers often look for the following skills:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;front-end&quot;&gt;Front-end&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different DOM manipulation technologies (Document API, jQuery)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JSON and AJAX requests (current with libraries and frameworks with a willingness to continue learning.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML5 and basic understanding of accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS feature support and organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backend&quot;&gt;Backend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Model-View-Controller architecture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic SQL and NoSQL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RESTful API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While education and experience is important, don’t forget to show off any ways you’ve been self-taught too. Include any repositories built from tutorials, a developer blog, or completed massive open online courses (MOOC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-a-story&quot;&gt;Tell a story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of ‘telling a story’ has become ubiquitous in fields like design and branding. We hear it so often it’s nearly lost its meaning. Yet, there is some fundamental importance to telling a story—it’s something we as humans connect with at our core. Displaying your skills and abilities through storytelling is the best way to make that connection and display your value. Every story has the same basic elements: characters and conflict. Your portfolio tells the story about you, the character, and your journey to overcome certain challenges through your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t include sketches and ideation just for the purpose of including artifacts — make sure that they support the story in some way, and demonstrate your creativity in solving the problem,”&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/design-ibm/design-portfolio-tips-and-tricks-from-a-hiring-manager-9bc42e7fcde7&quot;&gt; says Gord Davidson&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Design and Studio Manager at IBM Studios Toronto. Davidson has many years of experience working with and hiring designers. He believes every portfolio should follow this storytelling theme—each in its own way, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-for-the-hiring-manager&quot;&gt;Design for the hiring manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examine your portfolio from the hiring manager’s perspective. They are sorting through dozens of portfolios in a sitting—what will make yours stand out? Do you create a cohesive, memorable experience for the hiring manager, from your cover letter to resume to portfolio? Do you answer questions the hiring manager is asking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you adding something to your portfolio, ask, “Does this contribute to the story I’m telling about my work skills and experience?” If the information you’re adding doesn’t highlight your work, skills, and who you are as an employee, leave it out. Don’t do have the worst portfolio ever. Be sure your portfolio does address these questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What problem did you solve?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did you get to the final product?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which tools did you use to get there?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What challenges did you overcome to reach this?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What purpose did this serve for the client?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to answer these questions in your portfolio in a concise manner. Keep the projects you display relevant to the role you’re applying. It needs to be memorable, but it also needs to be something they actually look at. You can always have more project examples or case studies available during the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-wait-to-get-paid&quot;&gt;Don’t wait to get paid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a new developer, you’re probably wondering: how do I show off my experience when I haven’t had a job yet? Remember, no one has to pay you to do a job for it to go in your portfolio. Show off your own work you’ve done for fun, do some pro bono work for a local organization, or show off your skills by ‘cloning’ an existing project. You don’t have to reinvent the wheel and come up with your own startup idea. Try redesigning a major brand’s website as if they hired you. Rebuild an existing app, but make it better by showing how you would solve some specific problem areas in the app and make the program flow better. Don’t be afraid to experiment! This shows hiring managers you can identify and solve problems creatively even without a project brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At ACA, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/&quot;&gt;build a project every day of class&lt;/a&gt;, and some bigger projects may take several sessions. From there, students can show off their work online or continue building on a project. We also provide our students with updates about freelance and volunteer opportunities to work on projects to help build out their portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apply-early-and-often&quot;&gt;Apply early and often&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, the biggest hurdle in landing that first job is not the portfolio, experience, or interview skills—it’s the lack of applications job seekers submit. They also tend to delay too long before submitting those applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We cannot stress enough that it’s the sheer number of applications [students] submit to different companies that will get them hired. It should not be uncommon to have 50+ applications out at a time because it surely isn’t uncommon to only hear back from five percent,” says Kevin. “It sounds stressful, but most anxiety experienced by students is the rush they feel to have their portfolio perfect when they should be more concerned with getting those first interviews, knowing that they may even bomb the first few.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the tech industry, the interviewing process can take several weeks for one company. You may not hear back from many companies for a while or at all. The more you jobs you apply for, and the earlier you start the process, the better your chances of getting that interview, and ultimately, the job.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you’re just starting out on your path as a developer without much or any experience to show off in your portfolio, the road ahead may seem daunting. So what makes a great developer portfolio? Let’s take a closer look at the important elements that make up a solid developer portfolio that will land you an interview.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Keys to Making a Tech Career Switch without Technical Experience</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/4-keys-to-making-a-career-switch-into-tech-without-technical-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Keys to Making a Tech Career Switch without Technical Experience" /><published>2019-02-21T19:58:04+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T19:58:04+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/4-keys-to-making-a-career-switch-into-tech-without-technical-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/4-keys-to-making-a-career-switch-into-tech-without-technical-experience/">&lt;p&gt;The tech industry seems to be holding steady as the place to be for job seekers and people looking to switch careers these days. Between the high job security, exciting work culture, competitive pay, and (in some cases) extremely generous and creative perks, tech companies make an excellent case for learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one common concern we hear at Austin Coding Academy from students and prospective students is this: “I work in the service industry and I don’t have any technical job experience. Will anyone even hire me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an understandable concern. After all, when you’re not working in the tech industry currently, it’s tough to get a handle on what the hiring landscape looks like. The good news is that tech companies and startups are regularly looking for people with coding skills, whether they’ve been at it for a few months or a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course your skills will become more developed (and more valuable to employers when it comes to salary negotiations) over years of working. Still, the absence of technical work on your resume should not scare you away or hold you back from getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Coding Academy students have all kinds of work backgrounds. Many people come to us looking to move away from their service industry jobs as servers, baristas, bartenders, hairdressers, etc. At first glance, it may not seem like these jobs have anything at all to do with working as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, service industry jobs and other non-technical work experiences build a broad range of soft skills that may serve you well in a technical position, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communication-skills&quot;&gt;Communication skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of strong communication skills in any corporate environment cannot be overstated. Regularly checking in to make sure that all stakeholders are up to speed on the status of a project—including expected completion dates, roadblocks you encounter along the way, and any number of other relevant concerns— is the mark of a professional, competent developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, strong communication skills are also necessary to function successfully in any service industry job as well. Whether you realize it or not, when you work in a fast-paced and demanding client-facing position (such as retail or food service), you develop and sharpen this skill set. The ability to communicate the status of orders with coworkers and customers in a timely fashion is a good indicator of how well you’d be able to use the same skills in an office setting..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resourcefulness&quot;&gt;Resourcefulness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even seasoned developers will occasionally run into an issue with their code that they’ve never encountered before. Understandably, this experience is even more common for beginners. That’s why it’s so important for developers to be resourceful thinkers. Being able to identify and draw from the resources that are available to you (whether that’s the advice of a more experienced team member or help from fellow developers on a Stack Exchange forum) is another mark of a strong contributor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also happens to be another skill that workers in the service industry can develop and strengthen on the job. Servers, baristas, and retail workers routinely have to get creative and find ways to meet customers’ high expectations on a tight timeline, using only the tools that are readily available to them. These experiences can translate into a smoother career transition than many of our students initially expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;focus&quot;&gt;Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a hairdresser accidentally makes a bigger cut than they meant to, there’s no going back. When a bartender pours the wrong drink, or a server brings out an incorrect food order, those resources often go to waste, and customers are likely to become irritable. People in service industry jobs learn quickly— often through early mistakes— how important it is to focus and get things right the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, strong developers know how pay attention to small details. When the difference between success and failure can come down to a handful of characters on a screen, having the ability to focus is crucial. Since experience is usually the best teacher, people with service industry backgrounds often have this skill down to a science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-soft-skills-are-more-important-than-you-think&quot;&gt;Your soft skills are more important than you think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication, focus, and resourcefulness are just a few of the soft skills that people in the service industry learn on the job. There are many other crucial traits these jobs can nurture, such as social skills, timeliness, and work ethic, to name a few. All these skills can help create a successful move into a technical position, even if your work experience doesn’t seem relevant at first glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re currently working in the service industry or another non-technical position, it’s understandable to feel intimidated by the thought of moving into a technical role. The truth is, though, that these job experiences may help make you a stronger developer down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soft skills you’ve picked up in your past work experiences may actually make you a desirable job candidate and a more successful, productive employee in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As the Austin tech scene continues to appeal to job seekers and people looking to switch careers, one common concern is: “I work in the service industry and I don’t have any technical job experience. Will anyone even hire me?”. While technical skills are important, there are other ways you can prepare yourself for a career switch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should Make Time to Learn to Code</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/why-you-should-make-time-to-learn-to-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should Make Time to Learn to Code" /><published>2019-02-21T19:34:55+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T19:34:55+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/why-you-should-make-time-to-learn-to-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/why-you-should-make-time-to-learn-to-code">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece was written by Erica Freedman, Content Specialist at SwitchUp.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/web-developers.htm&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, Web Developers across the United States make an average of $67,990 annually. This increasingly popular career path currently has over 162,000 jobs ranging from entry to senior level. So how do you fit &lt;strong&gt;web development training&lt;/strong&gt; into your day? Use this guide to explore the field, the job opportunities associated, and offerings within Austin Coding Academy’s program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunities-after-bootcamp&quot;&gt;Opportunities After Bootcamp&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web Development is an all encompassing term that focuses on the development of websites and web applications. Jobs may include web-based internet applications, social networking platforms, and electronic business platforms. Individuals trained in this field may work in web content development, web engineering, cyber security, or design. This training could also lead to the development of CRM systems, still considered a new branch of web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this day an age, virtually every business and individual contractor needs a website and payment platform to operate. This means more jobs for individuals like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Growth&lt;/strong&gt;: “The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/web-developers.htm&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/a&gt; projects about 13 percent employment growth for web developers by 2026. During that period, about &lt;strong&gt;21,300 new jobs&lt;/strong&gt; will need to be filled in an industry that already &lt;strong&gt;has roughly 162,900 positions&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Developer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Web developers&lt;/strong&gt;, also called &lt;strong&gt;web&lt;/strong&gt; designers or webmasters, design and maintain websites. You might design and develop basic website layout or advanced interactive website features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Web&lt;/strong&gt; application development has certain characteristics that make it different from traditional software, information system, or computer application development. &lt;strong&gt;Web engineering&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on the specifics of application development that apply to websites and their offsets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-web-development-can-boost-your-career&quot;&gt;Learning Web Development Can Boost Your Career&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Development has one of the highest job opening rates in the world.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/pictures/mjd45eilkk/web-development/#7864f8833180&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forbes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; published an article celebrating Web Development as one of the top freelance careers, with freelancers earning an average of $36 to $40 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/quora/2017/04/10/five-reasons-why-web-development-is-a-better-career-path-than-machine-learning/#378689f53ddf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have even claimed that learning Web Development is more valuable than learning Machine Learning for a few reasons: There are countless jobs, it is a simple and straightforward working process, it is creative and fun, and is also extremely lucrative. This linear career path makes room for learning new working systems and trends, while also leaving space for creative liberty and thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;austin-coding-academy-web-development-program&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy Web Development Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web development courses at Austin Coding Academy fit into virtually every schedule, as these courses take place at night. They also offer courses for beginners, intermediate learners and those looking to begin web development careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web 101: The Web 101 Course at Austin Coding Academy is ideal for beginners. This course focuses on HTML, CSS and Javascript. Students will graduate with the ability to begin freelancing as a web designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;211: JavaScript Full Stack: This intermediate course aims to further develop HTML and CSS skills and advances into building applications. This class is two nights a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;311 JavaScript Full Stack: The Austin Coding Academy advanced course takes intermediate students and develops their skills in advanced programs such as Node.js and React.js. Graduates of this program will be able to develop full-fledged web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-do-students-say&quot;&gt;So What Do Students Say?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, on &lt;a href=&quot;http://switchup.org/&quot;&gt;SwitchUp&lt;/a&gt;, Austin Coding Academy has a &lt;strong&gt;5 out of 5 star rating&lt;/strong&gt; based on 21 verified student reviews. Students find this program balanced, fair, exciting, useful and thorough. Students graduate and land great jobs all over the country. See a sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student Review: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchup.org/bootcamps/austin-coding-academy?review_id=11842&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Balanced, Fair and Caring”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At Austin Coding Academy every teacher, admin and TA cares about its students future. They don’t want your money if you are not learning so they are constantly working to keep their curriculum up-to-date and challenging. I’ve seen this in practice as both a student and as a TA, they are always improving. Their teachers are working professionals with real-world experience and stories to share in class. And they always care about how the students do in class and in the future. The curriculum is solid and will give you a confident knowledge base web development.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you convinced? If you would like to read more student reviews visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchup.org/bootcamps/austin-coding-academy?review_id=11842&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy&lt;/a&gt; school page on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchup.org/bootcamps/austin-coding-academy?review_id=11842&quot;&gt;SwitchUp&lt;/a&gt;. To get started on your application, &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; and get one step closer to the web development job you’ve been dreaming about!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Web Developers across the United States make an average of $67,990 annually. This increasingly popular career path currently has over 162,000 jobs ranging from entry to senior level. Find out how you can fit learning to code into your day:</summary></entry></feed>