<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-15T22:28:25+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">What Will You Make as a Full-Time Web Developer?</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-web-developer-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Will You Make as a Full-Time Web Developer?" /><published>2019-02-15T22:25:36+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T22:25:36+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-web-developer-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-web-developer-1/">&lt;p&gt;As a prospective developer, you may have a lot of questions about your salary. What will your first year’s salary be? How will your salary change throughout your career? What factors will contribute the most to your compensation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at how much money you can expect to earn working as a web developer and how experience, education, location, and coding specialty can all impact your salary. Knowing what your skill is worth will help you negotiate better pay as you advance through your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-impact-of-experience-on-your-salary&quot;&gt;The Impact of Experience on Your Salary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in any other job, more experience as a developer will often lead to higher pay. Perfecting your craft means you can work on more meaningful projects and require less supervision from managers. Here’s how your salary will change as you move throughout your career:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-job-little-to-no-experience&quot;&gt;First Job (little to no experience)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding students are often very interested in their first job’s salary because they’ve worked so hard to earn it. In an entry-level job title like junior programmer or software developer, a first-year developer will earn a $64k average salary (ranging from $58k to $77k). This is consistent with&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchup.org/bootcamps/austin-coding-academy&quot;&gt;ACA’s average graduate salary.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;experienced-5-years&quot;&gt;Experienced (5 years)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With five years of experience, you will have mastered many of your day-to-day tasks. Increased efficiency means you can advance to positions such as a senior developer or lead software engineer. At this point, you can expect to earn an average of $80k per year, ranging from $69k to $100k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mid-career-6-14-years&quot;&gt;Mid-Career (6-14 years)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-career, many developers will move to managerial roles and away from technical ones. These roles will require you to know how to manage people, sell clients, oversee projects, analyze results, and plan for future initiatives. Average salaries for these positions are usually over $100k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;late-career-15-years&quot;&gt;Late Career (15+ years)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in a developer’s career, they may have climbed the corporate ladder into positions like software development manager, vice president of information technology, or even chief information officer (CIO). Salaries for these positions range between $120k to $170k. You can increase your salary even more by starting your own company or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/highest-paying-jobs-at-google&quot;&gt;working for a tech giant&lt;/a&gt; like Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-factors-affecting-salary&quot;&gt;Other factors affecting salary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;schooling&quot;&gt;Schooling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does education have a big impact on your salary? It can. It will depend on how useful your new skills are and how much time you’re required to invest before you start work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common options for coding education are either a&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/computer-science-degree-vs.-austin-coding-academy-which-is-the-best-choice-for-aspiring-developers&quot;&gt; coding bootcamp or a computer science degree&lt;/a&gt;. Bootcamp graduates tend to learn more in-demand skills and can, therefore, earn &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bloc.io/comparing-salaries-for-coding-bootcamps-vs-computer-science-degrees/&quot;&gt;$6,000 more&lt;/a&gt; than degree holding developers on average. Most companies are &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.indeed.com/2017/05/02/what-employers-think-about-coding-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;just as likely to hire&lt;/a&gt; bootcamp graduates as they are college graduates. Hiring manager&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.triplebyte.com/bootcamps-vs-college&quot;&gt; Ammon Bartram writes&lt;/a&gt;, “All in all, we’ve had roughly equivalent success working with the two groups.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One major difference between bootcamps and bachelor’s degrees is the time they take to complete. ACA’s bootcamp, for example, takes only nine months, compared to four years for the typical bachelor’s degree. With three additional years of working experience, you’ll learn a lot of skills on the job, giving you a strong competitive advantage over people who got a four-year degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;location&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where you work will have a large impact on your salary. For example, coders in California can &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech.co/much-software-developer-make-every-state-2015-03&quot;&gt;earn 83% more&lt;/a&gt; than coders in North Dakota, but that high salary won’t go as far in California as it would in a less-expensive state. Be careful to consider cost of living into your decision-making process when choosing where you want to live and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, developers in Austin will earn a $79k salary. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/oes/current/oes151132.htm&quot;&gt;occupation wage chart&lt;/a&gt; can help you compare the average Texan developer’s salary and cost of living to those of their counterparts working in other states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coding-specialty&quot;&gt;Coding Specialty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coding languages you learn could affect your job title and income. Use a tool like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tiobe.com/tiobe-index/&quot;&gt;TIOBE index&lt;/a&gt; to research the market demand for different coding languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACA teaches its students JavaScript and C# because these languages will give graduates a large salary and in-demand skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unsure which skills would be the best fit for your goals, here’s an article we’ve written to help you &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/which-aca-track-is-right-for-you&quot;&gt;decide which coding track is the right choice for you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-your-software-developer-career-track-today&quot;&gt;Start Your Software Developer Career Track Today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get these high salaries as a software engineer, you’ll need to learn the skills first. &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy’s bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; is the fastest and most effective way to start your career as a full-time developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will learn the most marketable skills at ACA, because all our teachers are also full-time working developers. After graduation, we’ll make sure you have a smooth transition into your first job by connecting you to our exclusive company job network. With our flexible night classes, you can study while keeping your day job. Best of all, ACA offers some of the most affordable tuition rates in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you waiting for? If you’re ready to make a positive change in your life by becoming a software developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;apply today&lt;/a&gt;. Our staff will work with you to help you turn your dreams into a reality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Let’s look at how much money you can expect to earn working as a web developer and how experience, education, location, and coding specialty can all impact your salary. Knowing what your skill is worth will help you negotiate better pay as you advance through your career.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Computer Science Degree vs. Coding Bootcamp: Which Is the Best Choice for Aspiring Developers?</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/computer-science-degree-vs-coding-bootcamp-which-is-the-best-choice-for-aspiring-developers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computer Science Degree vs. Coding Bootcamp: Which Is the Best Choice for Aspiring Developers?" /><published>2019-02-11T21:28:54+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T21:28:54+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/computer-science-degree-vs-coding-bootcamp-which-is-the-best-choice-for-aspiring-developers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/computer-science-degree-vs-coding-bootcamp-which-is-the-best-choice-for-aspiring-developers/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re just starting to consider pursuing a career as a developer, you’ve probably done your fair share of research. What does a typical day look like? How much money can I expect to make? What do I need to learn before I can apply for a position?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on where you’re looking online or who you’re talking to, you may have picked up that many developers have a bachelor’s degree (or higher) in computer science. In fact, until recently, a CS degree was the most direct path into a career in code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while many people working as developers have degrees in computer science, that doesn’t mean it’s a requirement. In fact, as the cost of college continues to rise with every passing year, there are fewer people who are willing or able to sink that kind of money (or time) into getting a degree. Meanwhile, the demand for capable developers hasn’t slowed down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where coding schools (like Austin Coding Academy) come into the picture. As more and more developers are needed to build the technology we depend on every day, and with fewer people able to press pause on their lives for four years, coding schools offer a way to get smart, motivated people up to speed so that they can enter the booming tech workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a job as a developer, you could opt for an expensive four-year education— including a bunch of random classes that have nothing to do with learning to code— or you could enroll in a coding school and get your coding career started sooner. Here’s why a coding school (like Austin Coding Academy) is a better option for people who want to become developers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-life-friendly-schedule&quot;&gt;More Life-Friendly Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students enrolled in a four-year degree program are generally unable to get their education while also holding down a full-time job. Between unusual course schedules, group projects, and study time for a wide variety of courses, most full-time college students can’t also be full-time employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students in coding schools like Austin Coding Academy, on the other hand, are able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/how-to-manage-time-effectively-when-you-dont-have-much-of-it&quot;&gt;continue working in their full-time jobs while taking classes in the evenings&lt;/a&gt;. Many ACA students have said that this factor gave them the peace of mind and financial flexibility to take the leap. In just two nights a week, ACA students get the education they need to transition out of their current day jobs and into their dream careers as full-time developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smaller-class-sizes&quot;&gt;Smaller Class Sizes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most four-year universities, students are required to take numerous prerequisite courses before they get to start learning any of the practical knowledge they’ll need in the working world. These entry-level classes are big money-makers for universities, since they can pack huge groups of students into a lecture hall with one professor. In these environments, there’s often very little (if any) personal interaction between the instructor and most of the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy, there isn’t a long list of prerequisite coursework to do before jumping in; there’s just &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; introductory course, and it has a limited class size just like our intermediate and advanced courses. We believe in keeping our classes small— a maximum of 20 students— so that each student is able to get individualized attention when they hit a snag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added bonus, these smaller class sizes mean our students get a chance to know and build friendships with their classmates. The result is a warm, positive environment where fellow students and instructors serve as a support network to encourage each other when the going gets tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lower-cost&quot;&gt;Lower Cost&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of a single year at a four-year university is enough to give most people a serious case of sticker shock. According to The College Board, the average cost of tuition and fees per year ranges from $9,410 at a public school (for in-state students) all the way up to a whopping $32,410 for private schools. These figures don’t include living expenses, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our goals at Austin Coding Academy is to provide the best value and return on investment for our students. That means keeping our class prices accessible to hard-working, motivated students, and it’s why we provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/tuition/&quot;&gt;affordable tuition&lt;/a&gt;— with no opaque fees tacked on top. Our students know exactly what they’re paying for: a high-quality, useful coding education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;professors-with-real-world-experience&quot;&gt;Professors with Real-World Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academia operates with its own antiquated rules, meaning that most university professors are &lt;em&gt;professors&lt;/em&gt; by trade. When students get a computer science degree, they’re likely to be taught by instructors who haven’t worked as developer recently— if ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, every Austin Coding Academy instructor is currently employed in the tech industry. Because of this, they’re able to adapt their instruction to reflect what’s happening in the industry at the moment. Even better: their students get to learn from people who know exactly what practical skills they’ll rely on to do their jobs every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;commitment-to-getting-you-a-job&quot;&gt;Commitment to Getting You a Job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of a four-year college education, students are rewarded with a diploma that proves they’ve taken the required coursework to graduate. This piece of paper may or may not help them get a job in their chosen field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of an ACA education, sure, there’s a certificate. But more importantly, our students leave with a professional network, an impressive portfolio demonstrating their new skills, and the support of our well-connected staff to help them find a job as a developer shortly after graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/get-to-know-aca-graduate-stephanie-singler&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent ACA graduate Stephanie had multiple job offers within a month of graduation— listen to her experience in her own words.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy, we’re committed to providing the best possible return on our students’ investments. When students enroll at ACA to get on the path to their dream jobs, we’re with them every step of the way— from the first class through to a new career (and beyond).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we make it a priority to help our graduates find high-paying jobs in the tech industry as soon as they finish their ACA coursework. We’re able to do this through the connections our former students, instructors, and other staff maintain with movers and shakers (and hiring managers) all over the tech industry in Austin. Our former students are currently working as JavaScript developers, full stack developers, QA engineers, and project managers, to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-aca-the-right-fit-for-you&quot;&gt;Is ACA the Right Fit for You?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to make a career change to get into a challenging, exciting, dynamic role in the tech sector, it’s important to remember that a computer science degree is not the only way to get there. An Austin Coding Academy education can get you the same results in less time, for less money, and without the risk involved in quitting your full-time job to enroll in school. Our knowledgeable and supportive staff will ensure that your coursework reflects what’s needed in the real world right now, so you can be sure that you’ve got the most in-demand skills in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.austincodingacademy.com/get-a-free-course-guide&quot;&gt;download our course guide&lt;/a&gt; and/or contact us today— we’d be happy to answer any of your questions or schedule time to give you an in-person tour of either of our campuses. Not living in Austin? We’ve got you! &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/why-acas-remote-classroom-is-a-better-choice&quot;&gt;Our remote classes&lt;/a&gt; provide the same quality instruction you’d get in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to take the next step toward your dream career? Our next session starts August 20. Apply here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you’re just starting to consider pursuing a career as a developer, you’ve probably done your fair share of research. What does a typical day look like? How much money can I expect to make? What do I need to learn before I can apply for a position?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Austin Coding Academy Partners with Lyft Drivers</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/announcements/austin-coding-academy-partners-with-lyft-drivers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Austin Coding Academy Partners with Lyft Drivers" /><published>2019-02-11T21:17:37+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T21:17:37+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/announcements/austin-coding-academy-partners-with-lyft-drivers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/announcements/austin-coding-academy-partners-with-lyft-drivers/">&lt;p&gt;Austin Coding Academy is partnering &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/lyft.com/lyftaustinonboarding/driver-deals/education&quot;&gt;with Lyft&lt;/a&gt;, one of Austin’s most popular ride-sharing apps, in an effort to make its classes more accessible to the same drivers who make our city more accessible to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everybody deserves access to a technical education and an opportunity to benefit from Austin’s booming tech industry,” says Austin Coding Academy CEO, Chris Lofton. “We’re excited to partner with Lyft to provide their drivers with this opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Coding Academy (ACA) will provide a discount to all current Lyft drivers who are interested in launching a career in technology. Currently, ACA offers tracks in Javascript, C#/.NET, and UI/UX and each track consists of three courses. Lyft drivers will be eligible for $225 off a single course or $675 off the total track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By tapping into a growing, but at times exclusive, tech scene, ACA is constantly looking for opportunities to foster inclusivity and diversity in tech through key program features such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part-time courses aimed at allowing working adults to continue to support themselves while making a meaningful career change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The most affordable full stack web development tuition in Austin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A curriculum that is researched, designed, and taught by local, full-time industry professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving accessibility to drivers who have already demonstrated a commitment to using their spare time to better support themselves represents another step towards promoting diversity of experience and identity – and one that has already seen success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sean Philippi has excelled as a student at ACA, where he’s on track to graduate as a full-stack Javascript developer in December of this year. As a Lyft driver and now an ACA student, Sean embodies the extra level of commitment necessary to thrive in a challenging environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Untitled%20design%20(31)-890896-edited.png&quot; alt=&quot;sean-philippi&quot; title=&quot;Sean Philippi, Lyft driver &amp;amp; ACA student&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I find the courses to be well-paced and challenging. I am very grateful for having discovered ACA.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Sean Philippi, Lyft driver &amp;amp; ACA student&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When self-teaching in the past, I’d often give up after being stuck for so long. I still get stuck now, but I have people that can help me get unstuck quickly, which is one of the most valuable parts of being in a classroom,” Sean says. “I find the courses to be well-paced and challenging. I am very grateful for having discovered ACA.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACA is excited to provide Lyft drivers with the opportunity to develop skills and transition to higher-paying tech jobs. With part-time evening courses and the most affordable full-stack coding education in the area, Austin Coding Academy is committed to increasing local access to careers in tech. ACA graduates work at companies like Microsoft, Dell, Oracle, Verizon and many Austin Startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apply-now&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APPLY NOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a current Lyft driver who is interested in enrolling in classes at Austin Coding Academy, you can find more information about course offerings &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/why/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To apply, click below and enter the promo code “LyftDriverATX” in the appropriate field within the application.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions that you would like answered, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;schedule a short Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt; with our admissions team, or book a&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.austincodingacademy.com/schedule-a-tour&quot;&gt; tour of either our North or Downtown Campus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Further verification of your status as a Lyft driver will be requested after your application is accepted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Austin Coding Academy is partnering with Lyft, one of Austin’s most popular ride-sharing apps, in an effort to make its classes more accessible to the same drivers who make our city more accessible to all.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ACA Partners with Austin Public Library to Teach Teens to Code</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/announcements/aca-partners-with-austin-public-library-to-teach-teens-to-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ACA Partners with Austin Public Library to Teach Teens to Code" /><published>2019-01-23T19:36:58+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-23T19:36:58+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/announcements/aca-partners-with-austin-public-library-to-teach-teens-to-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/announcements/aca-partners-with-austin-public-library-to-teach-teens-to-code/">&lt;p&gt;On Monday night, Austin Coding Academy teamed up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://library.austintexas.gov/&quot;&gt;Austin Public Library&lt;/a&gt; to host a free coding event for local teenagers at the Central Library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Glitch: Coding Made Easy” is a 2-hour workshop whose goal is to inspire teens to explore careers in computer programming. We are proud to partner with APL to introduce a creative an in-demand skill for their future careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the students began the night with no coding experience, but after 120 minutes, all were able to create and deploy their own websites on a topic they were interested in. “We covered HTML, CSS, and JavaScript,” said ACA’s CEO Chris Lofton, who instructed the class. “One student built her website about books and movies she loves. Another student’s website consisted of pictures from all the places she traveled. One even built a site that included instructions on how to play his favorite video game!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Teenage student builds website displaying places she’s traveled](https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/hs-fs/hubfs/IMG_9845.jpg?width=595&amp;amp;name=IMG_9845.jpg =595x)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the course, students worked together to solve different problems they encountered while building their sites. Each of the students was fully engaged through the process of brainstorming, designing, and building their pages while getting feedback and guidance from their instructor. By the end of the night, they each had an active website to take home and continue building on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We could not be any happier with the event,” said APL Youth Technology Librarian Adrian Perez. “One particular student, Tori, attended the program we had the next night and told me that she always wanted to major in music, but after Glitch and joining a robotics club last month, she wants to go into coding as well – specifically music software. She proudly told us that she already knows what she wants to do with her life – and she’s only 13!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye on Austin Public Library’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.austintexas.gov/events/calendar?loc=3939&quot;&gt;events calendar&lt;/a&gt; for more Austin Coding Academy library workshops coming down the pipeline. It is ACA’s core mission to make tech careers accessible to everyone, and we think giving teens exposure to the challenges and rewards of coding will illuminate this as a possible path they could take after high school. “We absolutely want to continue planning events with ACA in the future,” said Perez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in having Austin Coding Academy provide coding classes for your group, reach out to us at info@austincodingacademy.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-pursue-a-career-in-tech-wed-love-to-talk-about-your-options&quot;&gt;Want to pursue a career in tech? We’d love to talk about your options:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;Schedule a Q&amp;amp;A session&lt;/a&gt; with a member of our admissions team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.austincodingacademy.com/schedule-a-tour&quot;&gt;Book a tour&lt;/a&gt; of one of our campuses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn more about our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/javascript/#our-program&quot;&gt;Javascript&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/csharp/&quot;&gt;C#/.NET&lt;/a&gt; Tracks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apply now below!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="learn to code" /><summary type="html">On Monday night, Austin Coding Academy teamed up with Austin Public Library to host a free coding event for local teenagers at the Central Library.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s the Difference Between JavaScript and C#?</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-s-the-difference-between-javascript-and-c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's the Difference Between JavaScript and C#?" /><published>2019-01-23T19:11:27+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-23T19:11:27+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-s-the-difference-between-javascript-and-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/what-s-the-difference-between-javascript-and-c/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering making the leap into a career in coding, there are so many factors to consider: should I get a bachelor’s degree in Computer Science or enroll in a coding school? Should I take an online class, an in-person class, or a remote class? And what language or specialty should I invest my time in learning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy, we currently offer two separate tracks for our students: JavaScript and C# .NET. We believe that there isn’t one “best” option; the right choice for each student has everything to do with their personal goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll take a closer look at both tracks, including general salary ranges, career outlooks, online communities, and job titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;caution-dontonlyconsider-salary-and-hiring-outlook&quot;&gt;Caution: Don’t &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; consider salary and hiring outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to lean heavily on salary data when choosing a coding language or specialty. But since your career takes up most of your waking hours, it’s important to consider which one will be most personally fulfilling and interesting to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at salary data on websites like Glassdoor and Payscale, you may notice a huge range of possible salaries. This is because, even with the same job title, there can be a lot of variation in job responsibilities and seniority. The best way to increase your salary potential is to be a key player on whatever team you end up on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s so important to choose a track you’re passionate about; your interest in your work will give you the motivation to go above and beyond what’s asked and expected of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;track-comparisons&quot;&gt;Track Comparisons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, let’s take a look at the two tracks offered at ACA, starting with JavaScript:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/javascript/&quot;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript (JS) is one of the most common coding languages, with about a third of software development jobs requiring some JavaScript knowledge. It’s also a relatively easy language to learn and has one of the largest communities to reach out to. The main purpose of JavaScript is to manipulate objects; any time something moves on a website, JavaScript is probably involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is a giant in the internet browser world. It works across all the most popular web browsers and phone apps because it uses variables to adapt its code to the platform. Coders use JS in applications like Safari, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer, and IOS/Android app platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s mostly an advantage, the cross-platform adaptability of JS can sometimes lead to compatibility issues. Because JavaScript is error-prone, proficient developers will have an easy time finding a job. Companies will even pay freelancers to double-check their JavaScript code through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bugcrowd.com/bug-bounty-list/&quot;&gt;bug bounty programs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;salary&quot;&gt;Salary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Range: $51k - $120k&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average: $75k - $100k&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting Average: $60k - $70k&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;job-outlook&quot;&gt;Job outlook&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job outlook for Javascript is strong. By 2020, there will be over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/computer-programming-is-a-trade-lets-act-like-it-1407109947&quot;&gt;one million unfilled Javascript positions&lt;/a&gt;. Developer jobs are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm&quot;&gt;projected to increase by 24%&lt;/a&gt; over the next 10 years— much higher than the 10% average in other fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript has one of the largest Overstack communities, and is the most tagged language in GitHub. You will have no problem finding resources or connecting with other working coders with such a sizable community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;example-job-titles&quot;&gt;Example job titles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-stack website developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;App developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website admin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript consultant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality assurance automation specialist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/csharp/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C#&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is an open-source Microsoft programming language. It’s a high-level language, which means it can handle a lot of the nitty-gritty technical stuff for you. Since C# is “static,” much of the code is explicit and clearly defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This static nature of C# makes it easy to understand at a glance, and is why it’s the go-to choice for projects that need consistency, simplicity, and scale. C# is also a fast language to run, which makes it a great candidate for programming video games through the Unity engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If developing games or consistent code snippets sounds appealing to you, C# may be a good choice. It’s also certain to provide you with robust job opportunities and community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;salary-1&quot;&gt;Salary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Range: $45k - $120k&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average: $70k - $95k&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting: $60k - $70k&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;job-outlook-1&quot;&gt;Job outlook&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fewer students choose to learn C# compared to JavaScript ,even though the projected growth rates are about the same (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm&quot;&gt;24%&lt;/a&gt;). This slight saturation of the JavaScript job market might lead to higher salaries for C# programmers in the next few years. C# also has interesting growth opportunity in the virtual-reality (VR) game market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;community-1&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The C# community is not quite as active as JavaScript, but it’s still the 4th largest on Overstack and the 7th largest meetup community. The Microsoft brand also provides many resources to help developers master the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;example-job-titles-1&quot;&gt;Example job titles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-stack web developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windows app developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information security specialist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C#.net developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Database manager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unreal developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-transferrable-skills&quot;&gt;Learn transferrable skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both tracks provide the foundational knowledge and transferrable skills for amazing web design. A working knowledge of C# will aid you in picking up JavaScript, and vice versa. UX designers’ great understanding of design principles helps make them effective website designers with even basic coding knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These interdisciplinary skills will help you impress hiring managers and improve your value when you start working with your new team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-these-resources-to-help-you-decide&quot;&gt;Use these resources to help you decide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking in all this information can feel like drinking water from a firehose. A great next step in your research process is to speak with real-life developers already in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources to connect you with working programmers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hear from former students: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/get-to-know-aca-graduate-stephanie-singler&quot;&gt;Stephanie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/student-highlight-12/19&quot;&gt;Lillian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/student-project-highlight-jon-gorman&quot;&gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/o/austin-coding-academy-10937668459&quot;&gt;Go to local coding events&lt;/a&gt; to pick the brains of other developers and/or to get some hands-on experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subscribe to the ACA blog to learn about the industry and see student stories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also connect with ACA graduates/students through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/austin-coding-academy-open-house-tickets-53310470051&quot;&gt;open house events&lt;/a&gt; or let our advisors answer your questions by &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;scheduling a quick call&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;experience-both-tracks-with-acas-web-101-class&quot;&gt;Experience both tracks with ACA’s Web 101 class&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many other programs expect students to choose an area of specialization right away. At Austin Coding Academy, we understand that a little bit of exposure to all your options will help make your decision more clear. That’s why we cover the basics of both tracks in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;intro to web class&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This intro course is great for the brand new student, all the way up to the student who’s dabbled with a few online tutorials. The ACA curriculum will solidify your coding knowledge, and our staff will provide you with the resources to help you land your dream job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know you want to start working towards an amazing coding career, don’t put it off. Let us &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;answer your questions&lt;/a&gt; or come &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.austincodingacademy.com/schedule-a-campus-tour&quot;&gt;tour the campus&lt;/a&gt;. See how ACA can help you on your path towards an exciting and rewarding career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already convinced? &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="JavaScript" /><category term="C#" /><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Classes" /><summary type="html">At Austin Coding Academy, we currently offer two separate tracks for our students: JavaScript and C# .NET. We believe that there isn’t one “best” option; the right choice for each student has everything to do with their personal goals and interests.</summary></entry></feed>